{
	"description": "Kanji for 日本漢字能力検定 5級",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "一冊", "answers": [ "いっさつ" ], "comment": "one copy (e.g. book)" },
	{ "question": "一層", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "much more; still more; all the more; more than ever\nsingle layer (or storey, etc.)\nrather; sooner; preferably" },
	{ "question": "上映", "answers": [ "じょうえい" ], "comment": "screening (a movie); showing\nto screen a movie" },
	{ "question": "不幸", "answers": [ "ふこう" ], "comment": "unhappiness; sorrow; misfortune; disaster; accident\ndeath (usu. of a relative); bereavement" },
	{ "question": "並ぶ", "answers": [ "ならぶ" ], "comment": "to line up; to stand in a line\nto rival; to match; to equal" },
	{ "question": "並列", "answers": [ "へいれつ" ], "comment": "running in parallel; lined up alongside\nparallel (electronics, computing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "主従", "answers": [ "しゅじゅう" ], "comment": "master and servant; lord and retainer; employer and employee" },
	{ "question": "乗降", "answers": [ "じょうこう" ], "comment": "getting on and off; embarking and disembarking" },
	{ "question": "乱す", "answers": [ "みだす" ], "comment": "to throw out of order; to disarrange; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "乳", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "milk\nbreast\nloop\ndecorative bump (on a hanging bell)" },
	{ "question": "仁愛", "answers": [ "じんあい" ], "comment": "benevolence; charity; love" },
	{ "question": "仁術", "answers": [ "じんじゅつ" ], "comment": "benevolent act; healing act" },
	{ "question": "住宅", "answers": [ "じゅうたく" ], "comment": "residence; housing; residential building" },
	{ "question": "体操", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "gymnastics; physical exercises; calisthenics" },
	{ "question": "供", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "companion; follower; attendant; retinue" },
	{ "question": "供える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to offer; to sacrifice; to dedicate" },
	{ "question": "価値", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "value; worth; merit" },
	{ "question": "保存", "answers": [ "ほぞん" ], "comment": "preservation; conservation; storage; saving (e.g. to disk); maintenance" },
	{ "question": "保障", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "guarantee; security; assurance; pledge; warranty" },
	{ "question": "俳優", "answers": [ "はいゆう" ], "comment": "actor; actress; player; performer" },
	{ "question": "俳句", "answers": [ "はいく" ], "comment": "haiku; 17-mora poem, usu. in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 morae" },
	{ "question": "借覧", "answers": [ "しゃくらん" ], "comment": "borrowing and reading" },
	{ "question": "値段", "answers": [ "ねだん" ], "comment": "price; cost" },
	{ "question": "傷", "answers": [ "きず" ], "comment": "wound; injury; cut; gash; bruise; scratch; scrape; scar\nchip; crack; scratch; nick\nflaw; defect; weakness; weak point\nstain (on one's reputation); disgrace; dishonor; dishonour\n(emotional) hurt; hurt feelings" },
	{ "question": "傷口", "answers": [ "きずぐち" ], "comment": "(opening of) a wound; (mouth of a) wound; cut" },
	{ "question": "優勝", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "overall victory; championship" },
	{ "question": "優良", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "superior; excellent; fine" },
	{ "question": "党首", "answers": [ "とうしゅ" ], "comment": "party leader" },
	{ "question": "全権", "answers": [ "ぜんけん" ], "comment": "plenipotentiary powers; full authority" },
	{ "question": "公私", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "public and private; official and personal; government and people" },
	{ "question": "公衆", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "the public; general public" },
	{ "question": "蔵", "answers": [ "くら" ], "comment": "warehouse; storehouse; cellar; magazine; granary; godown; depository; treasury; elevator\npossession; ownership\n(former) Ministry of Finance\nTibet; Tibetan people" },
	{ "question": "内蔵", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "internal (e.g. disk); built-in; equipped (with)" },
	{ "question": "内閣", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "cabinet; (government) ministry" },
	{ "question": "冊子", "answers": [ "さっし" ], "comment": "book; booklet; story book; pamphlet; notebook\nwritten work (esp. a bound text, as opposed to a scroll)\na text written entirely in kana\ngraphic novel (esp. one created between the 12th and 19th centuries)\nnotebook (for practicing kana, drawing pictures, etc.)\nrough draft" },
	{ "question": "処理", "answers": [ "しょり" ], "comment": "processing; dealing with; treatment; disposition; disposal" },
	{ "question": "処置", "answers": [ "しょち" ], "comment": "measure; step; dealing with\nmedical treatment" },
	{ "question": "分担", "answers": [ "ぶんたん" ], "comment": "apportionment; allotment; share" },
	{ "question": "刻む", "answers": [ "きざむ" ], "comment": "to mince; to cut fine; to chop up; to hash; to shred\nto carve; to engrave; to chisel; to notch\nto tick away (time); to beat out (e.g. rhythm); to record the passing moments\nto etch (into one's mind); to remember distinctly\nto have tattooed\nto torment" },
	{ "question": "割る", "answers": [ "わる" ], "comment": "to divide\nto cut; to halve; to separate; to split; to rip\nto break; to crack; to smash\nto dilute\nto fall below\nto discount\nto step over (a line, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "割合", "answers": [ "わりあい" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; percentage; proportion\ncomparatively\ncontrary to expectations" },
	{ "question": "創造", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "creation" },
	{ "question": "劇", "answers": [ "げき" ], "comment": "drama; play\npowerful drug" },
	{ "question": "劇的", "answers": [ "げきてき" ], "comment": "dramatic; exciting; touching\nextreme" },
	{ "question": "加盟", "answers": [ "かめい" ], "comment": "participation; affiliation" },
	{ "question": "勤む", "answers": [ "つとむ" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "勤勉", "answers": [ "きんべん" ], "comment": "diligent; industrious" },
	{ "question": "勤務", "answers": [ "きんむ" ], "comment": "service; duty; work" },
	{ "question": "区域", "answers": [ "くいき" ], "comment": "limits; boundary; domain; zone; sphere; territory\narea (e.g. in programming languages)" },
	{ "question": "単純", "answers": [ "たんじゅん" ], "comment": "simplicity; simple; uncomplicated" },
	{ "question": "危ない", "answers": [ "あぶない" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow\nlook out!; watch out!" },
	{ "question": "危機", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "crisis; danger; risk" },
	{ "question": "危険", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "danger; peril; hazard\nrisk" },
	{ "question": "卵", "answers": [ "たまご" ], "comment": "eggs; egg; spawn; roe\nhen egg\n(an expert) in the making\nbeginning; origin; infancy\negg; eggshell\novum; ovule; egg cell" },
	{ "question": "厳しい", "answers": [ "きびしい" ], "comment": "severe; strict; rigid; unsparing; relentless\nintense (e.g. cold); harsh; tough" },
	{ "question": "厳格", "answers": [ "げんかく" ], "comment": "severe; rigid; stern; strictness; rigor; rigour; austerity" },
	{ "question": "厳禁", "answers": [ "げんきん" ], "comment": "strict prohibition; ban; interdiction" },
	{ "question": "参拝", "answers": [ "さんぱい" ], "comment": "visit to a shrine or temple; paying homage at a shrine or temple" },
	{ "question": "収入", "answers": [ "しゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "income; receipts; revenue" },
	{ "question": "収納", "answers": [ "しゅうのう" ], "comment": "storage; putting or stowing away\nreceipt (of funds, payment, etc.)\nharvesting" },
	{ "question": "収録", "answers": [ "しゅうろく" ], "comment": "compilation; editing\nrecording" },
	{ "question": "取捨", "answers": [ "しゅしゃ" ], "comment": "choice; option; rejection or adoption" },
	{ "question": "口紅", "answers": [ "くちべに" ], "comment": "lipstick" },
	{ "question": "口腹", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "appetite\ndistinction between what is thought and what is said" },
	{ "question": "否定", "answers": [ "ひてい" ], "comment": "negation; denial; repudiation; disavowal\nNOT operation" },
	{ "question": "否決", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "rejection; negation; voting down" },
	{ "question": "吸う", "answers": [ "すう" ], "comment": "to smoke; to breathe in; to inhale\nto suck; to sip; to slurp\nto absorb; to soak up\nto kiss" },
	{ "question": "吸収", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "absorption; suction; attraction" },
	{ "question": "吸飲", "answers": [ "きゅういん" ], "comment": "sucking in" },
	{ "question": "呼ぶ", "answers": [ "よぶ" ], "comment": "to call out (to); to call; to invoke\nto summon (a doctor, etc.)\nto invite\nto designate; to name; to brand\nto garner (support, etc.); to gather\nto take as one's wife" },
	{ "question": "呼吸", "answers": [ "こきゅう" ], "comment": "breathing; respiration\nknack; trick; secret (of doing something)\nharmony; balance; synchronization; accord\nshort interval; short pause" },
	{ "question": "善処", "answers": [ "ぜんしょ" ], "comment": "handling carefully; tiding over; making best of; using discretion" },
	{ "question": "善悪", "answers": [ "ぜんあく" ], "comment": "good and evil" },
	{ "question": "善良", "answers": [ "ぜんりょう" ], "comment": "goodness; excellence; virtue" },
	{ "question": "回覧", "answers": [ "かいらん" ], "comment": "circulation (esp. documents); sending round" },
	{ "question": "困る", "answers": [ "こまる" ], "comment": "to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped" },
	{ "question": "困苦", "answers": [ "こんく" ], "comment": "privation; hardship" },
	{ "question": "困難", "answers": [ "こんなん" ], "comment": "difficulty; hardship; trouble; distress" },
	{ "question": "地域", "answers": [ "ちいき" ], "comment": "area; region" },
	{ "question": "地層", "answers": [ "ちそう" ], "comment": "stratum; geological formation; layer; bed (coal, gravel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "地蔵", "answers": [ "じぞう" ], "comment": "Kshitigarbha (bodhisattva who looks over children, travellers and the underworld) (travelers); Ksitigarbha; Jizo" },
	{ "question": "垂れる", "answers": [ "たれる" ], "comment": "to hang; to droop; to dangle; to sag; to lower; to pull down\nto leave behind (at death); to give; to confer\nto drip; to ooze; to trickle; to drop\nto droop; to hang down; to weep" },
	{ "question": "垂直", "answers": [ "すいちょく" ], "comment": "vertical\nperpendicular" },
	{ "question": "城門", "answers": [ "じょうもん" ], "comment": "castle gate" },
	{ "question": "墓穴", "answers": [ "ぼけつ" ], "comment": "grave (pit)" },
	{ "question": "天守閣", "answers": [ "てんしゅかく" ], "comment": "castle tower; keep; donjon" },
	{ "question": "奮う", "answers": [ "ふるう" ], "comment": "to muster (e.g. one's courage); to call forth; to rouse up\nto be enlivened; to be invigorated" },
	{ "question": "奮起", "answers": [ "ふんき" ], "comment": "stirring; rousing oneself" },
	{ "question": "姿", "answers": [ "すがた" ], "comment": "figure; form; shape\nappearance; dress; guise\nstate; condition; picture; image\nform (of a waka)\ndressed in ...; wearing ..." },
	{ "question": "姿勢", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "attitude; posture; stance; approach; carriage (of the body)" },
	{ "question": "姿見", "answers": [ "すがたみ" ], "comment": "dresser; full-length mirror" },
	{ "question": "存分", "answers": [ "ぞんぶん" ], "comment": "to one's heart's content; as much as one wants" },
	{ "question": "存在", "answers": [ "そんざい" ], "comment": "existence; being" },
	{ "question": "存続", "answers": [ "そんぞく" ], "comment": "duration; continuance" },
	{ "question": "孝行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "filial piety" },
	{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "universe; cosmos; space" },
	{ "question": "宗教", "answers": [ "しゅうきょう" ], "comment": "religion; religious affiliation; belief; faith; creed\nreligious activity" },
	{ "question": "官庁", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "government office; government agency; authorities" },
	{ "question": "定刻", "answers": [ "ていこく" ], "comment": "appointed time; timetable; schedule" },
	{ "question": "宝", "answers": [ "たから" ], "comment": "treasure" },
	{ "question": "宝刀", "answers": [ "ほうとう" ], "comment": "treasured sword" },
	{ "question": "宝庫", "answers": [ "ほうこ" ], "comment": "treasury; treasure house" },
	{ "question": "宣伝", "answers": [ "せんでん" ], "comment": "publicity; advertisement; advertising; propaganda" },
	{ "question": "宣言", "answers": [ "せんげん" ], "comment": "declaration; proclamation; announcement" },
	{ "question": "密度", "answers": [ "みつど" ], "comment": "density" },
	{ "question": "密集", "answers": [ "みっしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; close formation; dense" },
	{ "question": "寸前", "answers": [ "すんぜん" ], "comment": "on the verge; on the brink; just in front of; just before" },
	{ "question": "寸断", "answers": [ "すんだん" ], "comment": "cut (tear) to pieces" },
	{ "question": "対策", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "measure; provision; step; countermeasure; counterplan; countermove" },
	{ "question": "専念", "answers": [ "せんねん" ], "comment": "absorption; giving undivided attention; devoting oneself (to)" },
	{ "question": "専用", "answers": [ "せんよう" ], "comment": "exclusive use; personal use; dedicated\nprivate (e.g. network)" },
	{ "question": "専門", "answers": [ "せんもん" ], "comment": "speciality; specialty; subject of study; expert; area of expertise" },
	{ "question": "射る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "to shoot (arrow, bolt, dart)" },
	{ "question": "射的", "answers": [ "しゃてき" ], "comment": "target practice" },
	{ "question": "将来", "answers": [ "しょうらい" ], "comment": "future (usually near); prospects" },
	{ "question": "将校", "answers": [ "しょうこう" ], "comment": "commissioned officer" },
	{ "question": "尊い", "answers": [ "とうとい", "たっとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "尊敬", "answers": [ "そんけい" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; reverence; honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "尊重", "answers": [ "そんちょう" ], "comment": "respect; esteem; regard" },
	{ "question": "就任", "answers": [ "しゅうにん" ], "comment": "inauguration; assumption of office" },
	{ "question": "就職", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "finding employment; getting a job" },
	{ "question": "尺八", "answers": [ "しゃくはち" ], "comment": "shakuhachi; end-blown fippleless bamboo flute\nblow job; fellatio" },
	{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at\nto be attentive; to pay attention\nto be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)" },
	{ "question": "展示", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display" },
	{ "question": "展開", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "development; evolution; progressing; unfolding\nexpansion; spreading out; extending; deployment; building up\nexpansion" },
	{ "question": "山頂", "answers": [ "さんちょう" ], "comment": "summit (of a mountain)" },
	{ "question": "巻く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to wind; to coil; to roll; to wear (e.g. turban, scarf)\nto envelope; to shroud\nto outflank; to skirt\nto link (verse)\nto move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up" },
	{ "question": "巻紙", "answers": [ "まきがみ" ], "comment": "paper roll; rolled letter paper" },
	{ "question": "帰宅", "answers": [ "きたく" ], "comment": "returning home" },
	{ "question": "幕内", "answers": [ "まくうち" ], "comment": "highest-ranking division" },
	{ "question": "干す", "answers": [ "ほす" ], "comment": "to air; to dry; to desiccate\nto drain (off)\nto drink up\nto deprive of a role, job, etc. (usu. in the passive)" },
	{ "question": "干潮", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "low tide; low water; ebb" },
	{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない" ], "comment": "very young\nchildish; immature" },
	{ "question": "幼児", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "infant; baby; child\nchild over 1 but not yet of school age" },
	{ "question": "庁舎", "answers": [ "ちょうしゃ" ], "comment": "government office building" },
	{ "question": "度胸", "answers": [ "どきょう" ], "comment": "courage; bravery; pluck; nerve; grit; guts" },
	{ "question": "座席", "answers": [ "ざせき" ], "comment": "seat" },
	{ "question": "延期", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "postponement; adjournment" },
	{ "question": "延長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "extension; elongation; prolongation; lengthening\nEnchou era (923.4.11-931.4.26)" },
	{ "question": "役割", "answers": [ "やくわり" ], "comment": "part; assigning (allotment of) parts; role; duties" },
	{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany" },
	{ "question": "従順", "answers": [ "じゅうじゅん" ], "comment": "obedient; gentle; meek; submissive; docile" },
	{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)" },
	{ "question": "忠告", "answers": [ "ちゅうこく" ], "comment": "advice; warning" },
	{ "question": "忠実", "answers": [ "ちゅうじつ" ], "comment": "faithfulness; devotion; loyalty; honesty; truth; fidelity\nsincerity; conscientiousness; diligence\nhealthiness; fitness\nfaithfulness; devotion" },
	{ "question": "意欲", "answers": [ "いよく" ], "comment": "will; desire; ambition; urge (e.g. creative urge)" },
	{ "question": "感激", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "deep emotion; impression; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "憲法", "answers": [ "けんぽう" ], "comment": "constitution" },
	{ "question": "我", "answers": [ "われ" ], "comment": "I; me\noneself\nyou\nprefix indicating familiarity or contempt\nmy; our; one's own\nobstinacy\natman; the self; the ego" },
	{ "question": "手段", "answers": [ "しゅだん" ], "comment": "means; way; measure" },
	{ "question": "批判", "answers": [ "ひはん" ], "comment": "criticism; judgement; judgment; comment" },
	{ "question": "批評", "answers": [ "ひひょう" ], "comment": "criticism; review; commentary" },
	{ "question": "担当", "answers": [ "たんとう" ], "comment": "being in charge (of an area of responsibility); being responsible (for a work role, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "拝む", "answers": [ "おがむ" ], "comment": "to assume the posture of praying; to press the palms and fingers of both hands together; to do reverence (e.g. before a statue of the Buddha); to pay one's respects\nto beg; to make a supplication\nto see (something or someone of high status)" },
	{ "question": "拡張", "answers": [ "かくちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; extension; enlargement; escape; ESC" },
	{ "question": "拡散", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "scattering; diffusion; spread (e.g. signal across the spectrum)" },
	{ "question": "指揮", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "command; direction" },
	{ "question": "捨てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "to throw away; to cast away; to dump; to discard\nto abandon; to desert; to leave\nto give up; to resign" },
	{ "question": "探す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "探検", "answers": [ "たんけん" ], "comment": "exploration; expedition" },
	{ "question": "推定", "answers": [ "すいてい" ], "comment": "presumption; assumption\nestimation" },
	{ "question": "推察", "answers": [ "すいさつ" ], "comment": "guess; conjecture; surmise" },
	{ "question": "推理", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "reasoning; inference; mystery or detective genre (movie, novel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "提供", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "offer; tender; program sponsoring; programme sponsoring; furnishing; provisioning; supply" },
	{ "question": "操作", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "operation; management; handling\nmanipulating to one's benefit" },
	{ "question": "改革", "answers": [ "かいかく" ], "comment": "reform; reformation; innovation" },
	{ "question": "政党", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "political party" },
	{ "question": "故郷", "answers": [ "こきょう" ], "comment": "home town; birthplace; native place; one's old home\nruins; historic remains" },
	{ "question": "故障", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "breakdown; failure; fault; accident; out of order\ndamage; hurt\nobjection; protest" },
	{ "question": "救済", "answers": [ "きゅうさい" ], "comment": "relief; aid; rescue; salvation; help\nsalvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)" },
	{ "question": "散乱", "answers": [ "さんらん" ], "comment": "dispersion; scattering; spreading out; diffusion" },
	{ "question": "散策", "answers": [ "さんさく" ], "comment": "walking; strolling; roaming; wandering; exploring" },
	{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "to show respect; to honour; to honor" },
	{ "question": "敬老", "answers": [ "けいろう" ], "comment": "respect for the aged" },
	{ "question": "敬語", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "honorific; term of respect; polite expression; honorific language" },
	{ "question": "方針", "answers": [ "ほうしん" ], "comment": "objective; plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "明朗", "answers": [ "めいろう" ], "comment": "cheerful; bright\nclear; clean; honest; fair" },
	{ "question": "星座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "constellation; star sign; zodiac sign" },
	{ "question": "映る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be reflected; to harmonize with (harmonise); to come out (photo); to be projected; to be displayed (on a screen)" },
	{ "question": "映像", "answers": [ "えいぞう" ], "comment": "reflection; image; picture (e.g. on a television); shot\nvideo; film; footage; clip; video recording\nimage in one's mind; mental picture" },
	{ "question": "晩秋", "answers": [ "ばんしゅう" ], "comment": "late autumn (fall)\nninth month of the lunar calendar" },
	{ "question": "暖冬", "answers": [ "だんとう" ], "comment": "mild winter; warm winter" },
	{ "question": "服装", "answers": [ "ふくそう" ], "comment": "garments; attire" },
	{ "question": "朗報", "answers": [ "ろうほう" ], "comment": "good news" },
	{ "question": "朗読", "answers": [ "ろうどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud; recitation" },
	{ "question": "机", "answers": [ "つくえ" ], "comment": "desk" },
	{ "question": "机上", "answers": [ "きじょう" ], "comment": "on the desk\ntheoretical; academic" },
	{ "question": "枚挙", "answers": [ "まいきょ" ], "comment": "enumeration" },
	{ "question": "枚数", "answers": [ "まいすう" ], "comment": "the number of flat things\nwin-loss difference which influences the ranking of wrestlers" },
	{ "question": "染める", "answers": [ "そめる" ], "comment": "to dye; to colour; to color" },
	{ "question": "株", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "stock; share\nstump\nroot; rootstock\nstrain (of bacteria, etc.)\ntradeable rank; goodwill\none's forte\nstake; post; pile; picket\nstump\nstump\ncounter for trees\nstump\nstump\nuseless item" },
	{ "question": "株式", "answers": [ "かぶしき" ], "comment": "stock (company)" },
	{ "question": "検討", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "consideration; examination; investigation; study; scrutiny; discussion; analysis; review" },
	{ "question": "模型", "answers": [ "もけい" ], "comment": "model; dummy; maquette" },
	{ "question": "模様", "answers": [ "もよう" ], "comment": "pattern; figure; design\nstate; condition\nconjecture of the current situation; the way it seems\nmodel; pattern; example\nindicates that that noun seems likely (e.g. rain or storm)\nframework (in go); territorial framework; moyo" },
	{ "question": "権利", "answers": [ "けんり" ], "comment": "right; privilege" },
	{ "question": "樹木", "answers": [ "じゅもく" ], "comment": "tree; trees and shrubs" },
	{ "question": "樹液", "answers": [ "じゅえき" ], "comment": "sap" },
	{ "question": "樹皮", "answers": [ "じゅひ" ], "comment": "(tree) bark" },
	{ "question": "歌詞", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "song lyrics; words of a song; libretto\nwords mainly used in songs or poetry" },
	{ "question": "正座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "seat of honor; seat of honour\nseiza; kneeling with the tops of the feet flat on the floor, and sitting on the soles" },
	{ "question": "正視", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "looking straight ahead\nviewing sincerely\nnormal vision" },
	{ "question": "正誤", "answers": [ "せいご" ], "comment": "right or wrong; correct and incorrect\ncorrection" },
	{ "question": "死亡", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "death; mortality\nto die; to pass away" },
	{ "question": "毎晩", "answers": [ "まいばん" ], "comment": "every night" },
	{ "question": "水源", "answers": [ "すいげん" ], "comment": "source of river; fountainhead" },
	{ "question": "決済", "answers": [ "けっさい" ], "comment": "settlement; payment of account" },
	{ "question": "沿う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to run along; to run beside\nto follow (a plan, etc.); to act in accordance with" },
	{ "question": "沿岸", "answers": [ "えんがん" ], "comment": "coast; shore; littoral" },
	{ "question": "沿革", "answers": [ "えんかく" ], "comment": "history; development" },
	{ "question": "泉", "answers": [ "いずみ" ], "comment": "spring; fountain" },
	{ "question": "法律", "answers": [ "ほうりつ" ], "comment": "law" },
	{ "question": "注射", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "injection" },
	{ "question": "注視", "answers": [ "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "gazing steadily at; observing (a person) closely; maintain a watch over" },
	{ "question": "洋裁", "answers": [ "ようさい" ], "comment": "(Western) dressmaking" },
	{ "question": "洗う", "answers": [ "あらう" ], "comment": "to wash; to cleanse; to rinse\nto inquire into; investigate\nto purify (one's heart)\nto lave (e.g. shore); to wash over (e.g. deck); to sweep" },
	{ "question": "洗面", "answers": [ "せんめん" ], "comment": "wash up (one's face); have a wash" },
	{ "question": "洗顔", "answers": [ "せんがん" ], "comment": "face-washing" },
	{ "question": "派手", "answers": [ "はで" ], "comment": "showy; loud; gay; flashy; gaudy" },
	{ "question": "海域", "answers": [ "かいいき" ], "comment": "area of ocean" },
	{ "question": "混乱", "answers": [ "こんらん" ], "comment": "disorder; chaos; confusion; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "済む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to finish; to end; to be completed\nto merely result in something less severe than expected\nto feel at ease\nto feel unease or guilt for troubling someone; to be sorry" },
	{ "question": "温暖", "answers": [ "おんだん" ], "comment": "warm; mild; temperate; warmth" },
	{ "question": "温泉", "answers": [ "おんせん" ], "comment": "spa; hot spring; onsen" },
	{ "question": "源", "answers": [ "みなもと" ], "comment": "source (of a river); fountainhead\nsource; origin; root\nsource; origin" },
	{ "question": "演奏", "answers": [ "えんそう" ], "comment": "musical performance" },
	{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "violent; furious; tempestuous\nextreme; intense; fierce; strong\nfervent; vehement\nincessant; relentless\nprecipitous; steep (archaism)" },
	{ "question": "灰", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "ash; ashes" },
	{ "question": "灰皿", "answers": [ "はいざら" ], "comment": "ashtray" },
	{ "question": "点呼", "answers": [ "てんこ" ], "comment": "roll-call; muster" },
	{ "question": "片側", "answers": [ "かたがわ" ], "comment": "one side" },
	{ "question": "片道", "answers": [ "かたみち" ], "comment": "one-way (trip)\none-way ticket" },
	{ "question": "牛乳", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(cow's) milk" },
	{ "question": "特権", "answers": [ "とっけん" ], "comment": "privilege; special right" },
	{ "question": "独奏", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "(instrumental) solo; recital" },
	{ "question": "班", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "group; party; team\nsquad; section" },
	{ "question": "班長", "answers": [ "はんちょう" ], "comment": "squad leader; group leader; team leader" },
	{ "question": "異なる", "answers": [ "ことなる" ], "comment": "to differ; to vary; to disagree" },
	{ "question": "異国", "answers": [ "いこく" ], "comment": "foreign country" },
	{ "question": "異論", "answers": [ "いろん" ], "comment": "different opinion; objection" },
	{ "question": "疑う", "answers": [ "うたがう" ], "comment": "to doubt; to distrust; to be suspicious of; to suspect" },
	{ "question": "疑問", "answers": [ "ぎもん" ], "comment": "question; problem; doubt; guess" },
	{ "question": "痛む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to hurt; to ache; to feel a pain\nto be injured; to be spoiled (e.g. food); to be damaged" },
	{ "question": "発展", "answers": [ "はってん" ], "comment": "development; growth; advancement; unfurling\nexpansion; extension; enlargement\nplaying around; having an active sex life" },
	{ "question": "発揮", "answers": [ "はっき" ], "comment": "exhibition; demonstration; show; display; manifestation" },
	{ "question": "登頂", "answers": [ "とうちょう" ], "comment": "climbing to the summit; summiting" },
	{ "question": "皇后", "answers": [ "こうごう" ], "comment": "(Japanese) empress; queen" },
	{ "question": "皇室", "answers": [ "こうしつ" ], "comment": "Imperial household" },
	{ "question": "皇居", "answers": [ "こうきょ" ], "comment": "Imperial Palace (of Japan); imperial residence" },
	{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto copulate (animals)\nto serve (food, etc.); to dish out\nto fill up; to pile up; to heap\nto prescribe; to administer; to dose out\nto put into (e.g. information in a report)\nto mark out (e.g. scale); to graduate (e.g. thermometer)\nto exaggerate; to apply heavy makeup" },
	{ "question": "盟友", "answers": [ "めいゆう" ], "comment": "sworn friend" },
	{ "question": "相棒", "answers": [ "あいぼう" ], "comment": "partner; pal; accomplice" },
	{ "question": "看板", "answers": [ "かんばん" ], "comment": "signboard; sign; billboard; hoarding; doorplate\ndraw; attraction; feature; highlight; spokesman; figurehead\nreputation (of a shop)\nappearance; look\nclosing time" },
	{ "question": "看病", "answers": [ "かんびょう" ], "comment": "nursing (a patient)" },
	{ "question": "看護", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "nursing; (army) nurse" },
	{ "question": "短縮", "answers": [ "たんしゅく" ], "comment": "shortening; contraction; reduction; curtailment; abbreviation" },
	{ "question": "砂地", "answers": [ "すなじ", "すなち" ], "comment": "sandy soil" },
	{ "question": "砂場", "answers": [ "すなば" ], "comment": "sand pit; sandbox" },
	{ "question": "砂糖", "answers": [ "さとう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "磁力", "answers": [ "じりょく" ], "comment": "magnetism; magnetic force" },
	{ "question": "磁石", "answers": [ "じしゃく" ], "comment": "magnet\ncompass" },
	{ "question": "磁針", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "magnetic needle" },
	{ "question": "神秘", "answers": [ "しんぴ" ], "comment": "mystery; mysteriousness; secret" },
	{ "question": "私服", "answers": [ "しふく" ], "comment": "civilian clothes; plain clothes; mufti\nplainclothes police officer" },
	{ "question": "秘密", "answers": [ "ひみつ" ], "comment": "secret; secrecy; confidentiality; privacy\nsecret; mystery\nesoteric teachings" },
	{ "question": "穀物", "answers": [ "こくもつ" ], "comment": "grain; cereal; corn" },
	{ "question": "穀類", "answers": [ "こくるい" ], "comment": "grains" },
	{ "question": "穴", "answers": [ "あな" ], "comment": "hole\ndeficit; shortage; missing person (in a team, meeting, etc.)\nvacancy; opening\nflaw\nprofitable place (or item, etc.) not well known by others\nupset victory (with a large payoff)\npit (of a theater)\nhiding place\nunderbelly (of society, etc.)\nass; arse; buttocks\nrear; end\nacupuncture point\nhole; notch" },
	{ "question": "空論", "answers": [ "くうろん" ], "comment": "abstract or impracticable theory" },
	{ "question": "窓", "answers": [ "まど" ], "comment": "window" },
	{ "question": "窓口", "answers": [ "まどぐち" ], "comment": "ticket window; teller window; counter\ncontact person; point of contact" },
	{ "question": "立憲", "answers": [ "りっけん" ], "comment": "constitutionalism" },
	{ "question": "筋肉", "answers": [ "きんにく" ], "comment": "muscle; sinew\nsinewy meat" },
	{ "question": "筋道", "answers": [ "すじみち" ], "comment": "reason; logic\nmethod; system; order; thread (e.g. of an argument)" },
	{ "question": "節穴", "answers": [ "ふしあな" ], "comment": "knothole; peep-hole\nbad eyes" },
	{ "question": "築城", "answers": [ "ちくじょう" ], "comment": "fortification; castle construction" },
	{ "question": "簡便", "answers": [ "かんべん" ], "comment": "handy; simple and easy" },
	{ "question": "簡単", "answers": [ "かんたん" ], "comment": "simple; easy; uncomplicated\nbrief; quick; light" },
	{ "question": "簡潔", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "brevity; conciseness; simplicity" },
	{ "question": "糖分", "answers": [ "とうぶん" ], "comment": "amount of sugar; sugar content" },
	{ "question": "系統", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "system\nlineage; ancestry; family line\ngroup (e.g. of colors) (colours); family (e.g. of languages); party; school (of thought)\nclose (evolutionary) relationship\na population sharing a common ancestor (in genetics); strain (e.g. bacterial)" },
	{ "question": "紅白", "answers": [ "こうはく" ], "comment": "red and white; colours for festive or auspicious occasions (colors)\nRed and White singing contest; annual contest between male and female popular singers on New Year's Eve (sponsored and broadcast by NHK)" },
	{ "question": "紅茶", "answers": [ "こうちゃ" ], "comment": "black tea" },
	{ "question": "納める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "納税", "answers": [ "のうぜい" ], "comment": "payment of taxes" },
	{ "question": "純情", "answers": [ "じゅんじょう" ], "comment": "pure heart; naivete; innocence" },
	{ "question": "絵巻物", "answers": [ "えまきもの" ], "comment": "picture scroll" },
	{ "question": "絹", "answers": [ "きぬ" ], "comment": "silk" },
	{ "question": "絹糸", "answers": [ "けんし", "きぬいと" ], "comment": "silk thread" },
	{ "question": "縦", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "the vertical; height\nfront-to-back; length\nnorth-to-south\nvertical (relationship); hierarchy\n(weaving) warp\nselfish; self-indulgent; arbitrary\neven if" },
	{ "question": "縦断", "answers": [ "じゅうだん" ], "comment": "running through (north-south); cutting across; travelling across\ncutting vertically; sectioning longitudinally" },
	{ "question": "縦横", "answers": [ "じゅうおう" ], "comment": "length and width; length and breadth; lengthwise and crosswise; longitude and latitude; vertical and horizontal\nfour cardinal points; every direction\nas one wishes; as one pleases; at will\nwarp and weft; warp and woof" },
	{ "question": "縮む", "answers": [ "ちぢむ" ], "comment": "to shrink; to contract; to diminish (in size)" },
	{ "question": "縮小", "answers": [ "しゅくしょう" ], "comment": "reduction; curtailment" },
	{ "question": "縮尺", "answers": [ "しゅくしゃく" ], "comment": "reduced scale; scaling" },
	{ "question": "署名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "signature" },
	{ "question": "翌日", "answers": [ "よくじつ" ], "comment": "next day" },
	{ "question": "翌週", "answers": [ "よくしゅう" ], "comment": "the following week; the next week" },
	{ "question": "聖", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "Saint; St.; S.\nsacred; holy; pure\nhighly virtuous monk\nmonk\nBuddhist solitary\nBuddhist missionary\nsaint (i.e. a virtuous person)\nemperor\nmaster; expert" },
	{ "question": "聖火", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "sacred fire (torch)\nOlympic flame" },
	{ "question": "肺活量", "answers": [ "はいかつりょう" ], "comment": "lung capacity" },
	{ "question": "背後", "answers": [ "はいご" ], "comment": "back; rear\nbackground; behind the scenes" },
	{ "question": "背景", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "background; scenery; backdrop; setting; circumstance; context\nbacking; support (from behind the scenes)" },
	{ "question": "背骨", "answers": [ "せぼね" ], "comment": "spine; backbone; spinal column" },
	{ "question": "胸", "answers": [ "むね" ], "comment": "chest; breast\nbreasts; bosom; bust\nheart\nlungs\nstomach\nheart; mind; feelings" },
	{ "question": "胸筋", "answers": [ "きょうきん" ], "comment": "pectoral (muscle)" },
	{ "question": "腹", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "abdomen; belly; stomach\nwomb\none's mind; one's real intentions; one's true motive\ncourage; nerve; willpower\ngenerosity; magnanimity\nfeelings; emotions\nwide middle part; bulging part\ninside; interior; inner part\nanti-node\ncounter for hard roe\ncounter for containers with bulging middles (pots, vases, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "臓器", "answers": [ "ぞうき" ], "comment": "internal organs; viscera; intestines" },
	{ "question": "臨時", "answers": [ "りんじ" ], "comment": "temporary; special; extraordinary" },
	{ "question": "自己", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "self; oneself" },
	{ "question": "至る", "answers": [ "いたる" ], "comment": "to arrive at (e.g. a decision); to reach (a stage); to attain\nto lead to (a place); to get to\nto come; to arrive; to result in" },
	{ "question": "至急", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "興奮", "answers": [ "こうふん" ], "comment": "excitement; stimulation; agitation; arousal" },
	{ "question": "若い", "answers": [ "わかい" ], "comment": "young; youthful\nimmature; green\nlow (number); small" },
	{ "question": "若気", "answers": [ "わかげ" ], "comment": "youthful impetuosity; youthful vitality\nmale homosexual's partner\nbuttocks; anus" },
	{ "question": "若葉", "answers": [ "わかば" ], "comment": "new leaves; fresh verdure" },
	{ "question": "苦痛", "answers": [ "くつう" ], "comment": "pain; agony; bitterness" },
	{ "question": "著名", "answers": [ "ちょめい" ], "comment": "well-known; noted; celebrated" },
	{ "question": "著しい", "answers": [ "いちじるしい" ], "comment": "striking; remarkable; considerable (used for good, bad, and neutral observations)" },
	{ "question": "著者", "answers": [ "ちょしゃ" ], "comment": "author (usu. of a particular book); writer" },
	{ "question": "蒸す", "answers": [ "むす" ], "comment": "to steam (food)\nto steam (food, towel, etc.)\nto be hot and humid; to be sultry" },
	{ "question": "蒸気", "answers": [ "じょうき" ], "comment": "steam; vapour; vapor\nsteamboat; steam locomotive" },
	{ "question": "蒸発", "answers": [ "じょうはつ" ], "comment": "evaporation\ndisappearance (of people intentionally concealing their whereabouts); unexplained disappearance" },
	{ "question": "蚕", "answers": [ "かいこ" ], "comment": "silkworm (Bombyx mori)" },
	{ "question": "裁く", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "to judge" },
	{ "question": "裁判", "answers": [ "さいばん" ], "comment": "trial; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "装置", "answers": [ "そうち" ], "comment": "equipment; installation; apparatus; device" },
	{ "question": "裏", "answers": [ "うら" ], "comment": "bottom (or another side that is hidden from view); undersurface; opposite side; reverse side\nrear; back; behind (the house)\nlining; inside\nout of sight; behind the scenes; in the shadows\nproof\nopposite (of a prediction, common sense, etc.)\ninverse (of a hypothesis, etc.)\nbottom (of an inning); last half (of an inning)" },
	{ "question": "裏庭", "answers": [ "うらにわ" ], "comment": "rear garden; back yard" },
	{ "question": "補う", "answers": [ "おぎなう" ], "comment": "to compensate for; to supplement" },
	{ "question": "補修", "answers": [ "ほしゅう" ], "comment": "maintenance; mending; repair" },
	{ "question": "補給", "answers": [ "ほきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; supplying; replenishment" },
	{ "question": "規律", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "order; observance; discipline\nrules; law; regulations" },
	{ "question": "視力", "answers": [ "しりょく" ], "comment": "eyesight" },
	{ "question": "観劇", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "theatre-going; theater-going" },
	{ "question": "観衆", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "spectators; onlookers; members of the audience" },
	{ "question": "解除", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "cancellation; rescinding; release; calling off; lifting (sanctions); delisting" },
	{ "question": "討論", "answers": [ "とうろん" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on; to pay a visit to" },
	{ "question": "訪問", "answers": [ "ほうもん" ], "comment": "call; visit" },
	{ "question": "訳", "answers": [ "わけ" ], "comment": "conclusion from reasoning, judgement or calculation based on something read or heard; reason; cause; meaning; circumstances; situation\ntranslation; version (e.g. \"English version\")" },
	{ "question": "訳す", "answers": [ "やくす" ], "comment": "to translate; to interpret" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる" ], "comment": "to write up\nto recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "誕生", "answers": [ "たんじょう" ], "comment": "birth; creation; formation" },
	{ "question": "誕生日", "answers": [ "たんじょうび" ], "comment": "birthday" },
	{ "question": "誠実", "answers": [ "せいじつ" ], "comment": "sincere; honest; faithful" },
	{ "question": "誠意", "answers": [ "せいい" ], "comment": "sincerity; good faith" },
	{ "question": "誤る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to err\nto mislead; to misguide" },
	{ "question": "誤飲", "answers": [ "ごいん" ], "comment": "accidental ingestion; swallowing something by mistake" },
	{ "question": "論文", "answers": [ "ろんぶん" ], "comment": "thesis; essay; treatise; paper; article" },
	{ "question": "諸国", "answers": [ "しょこく" ], "comment": "various countries; various regions; various provinces" },
	{ "question": "警報", "answers": [ "けいほう" ], "comment": "alarm; warning" },
	{ "question": "警察", "answers": [ "けいさつ" ], "comment": "police\npolice officer\npolice station" },
	{ "question": "警笛", "answers": [ "けいてき" ], "comment": "horn; alarm; whistle; foghorn" },
	{ "question": "負傷", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "injury; wound" },
	{ "question": "負担", "answers": [ "ふたん" ], "comment": "burden; charge; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "貯蔵", "answers": [ "ちょぞう" ], "comment": "storage; preservation" },
	{ "question": "貴族", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "noble; aristocrat" },
	{ "question": "貴重", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "precious; valuable" },
	{ "question": "賃貸", "answers": [ "ちんたい" ], "comment": "lease; rent; hire" },
	{ "question": "賃金", "answers": [ "ちんぎん" ], "comment": "wages\ncash payment of rent" },
	{ "question": "資源", "answers": [ "しげん" ], "comment": "resources" },
	{ "question": "車窓", "answers": [ "しゃそう" ], "comment": "train window; car window" },
	{ "question": "近視", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "myopia; shortsightedness; nearsightedness" },
	{ "question": "返済", "answers": [ "へんさい" ], "comment": "repayment; reimbursement; refund; redemption" },
	{ "question": "週刊誌", "answers": [ "しゅうかんし" ], "comment": "weekly publication; weekly magazine" },
	{ "question": "遊覧", "answers": [ "ゆうらん" ], "comment": "sightseeing" },
	{ "question": "運賃", "answers": [ "うんちん" ], "comment": "(passenger) fare\nfreight rates; shipping expenses" },
	{ "question": "過激", "answers": [ "かげき" ], "comment": "extreme; radical" },
	{ "question": "遺産", "answers": [ "いさん" ], "comment": "inheritance; bequest; legacy; heritage" },
	{ "question": "郵便", "answers": [ "ゆうびん" ], "comment": "mail service; postal service; mail; post\nmail; postal matter; postal items" },
	{ "question": "郷土", "answers": [ "きょうど" ], "comment": "native place; birth-place; one's old home\nprovince; region; locality" },
	{ "question": "郷里", "answers": [ "きょうり" ], "comment": "birth-place; home town" },
	{ "question": "針", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "needle; pin\nhook\nstinger; thorn\nhand (e.g. clock, etc.); pointer\nstaple (for a stapler)\nneedlework; sewing\nmalice\ncounter for stitches" },
	{ "question": "針金", "answers": [ "はりがね" ], "comment": "wire" },
	{ "question": "鉄棒", "answers": [ "てつぼう" ], "comment": "iron rod; iron bar; iron club\nhorizontal bar (gymnastics)\nmetal rod; metal bar; iron rod; crowbar\niron club; iron staff with rings on top (traditionally used by night watchmen)" },
	{ "question": "鉄骨", "answers": [ "てっこつ" ], "comment": "steel frame; steel beam; steel girder" },
	{ "question": "鋼鉄", "answers": [ "こうてつ" ], "comment": "steel" },
	{ "question": "閉じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.); to shut" },
	{ "question": "閉店", "answers": [ "へいてん" ], "comment": "closing up shop (for the day)\nstopping business; going out of business" },
	{ "question": "開幕", "answers": [ "かいまく" ], "comment": "raising the curtain\nopening (of an event); start of a season" },
	{ "question": "閣議", "answers": [ "かくぎ" ], "comment": "cabinet meeting" },
	{ "question": "降る", "answers": [ "ふる", "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend; to go down; to come down\nto be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.)\nto pass (of time)\nto surrender; to capitulate\n(often in neg. form) to be less than; to be inferior to\nto have the runs; to have diarrhea\nto pass (in stool); to be discharged from the body\nto precipitate; to fall (e.g. rain)" },
	{ "question": "降下", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "fall; descent; (plane) landing; (atmos.) depression" },
	{ "question": "陛下", "answers": [ "へいか" ], "comment": "your Majesty; his Majesty; her Majesty" },
	{ "question": "除く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to eliminate; to eradicate\nto exclude; to except" },
	{ "question": "除去", "answers": [ "じょきょ" ], "comment": "removal; getting rid of" },
	{ "question": "階段", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "stairs; stairway; staircase" },
	{ "question": "障子", "answers": [ "しょうじ" ], "comment": "shoji (paper sliding door)" },
	{ "question": "雑誌", "answers": [ "ざっし" ], "comment": "journal; magazine; periodical" },
	{ "question": "難しい", "answers": [ "むずかしい" ], "comment": "difficult; hard; troublesome; complicated; serious (disease, problem, etc.)\nfussy; particular; fastidious; hard to please; displeased\ngloomy; glum; sullen; serious (look)\ndirty; unclean; filthy; detestable\nunpleasant; uncomfortable; creepy; spooky" },
	{ "question": "難易", "answers": [ "なんい" ], "comment": "difficulty; relative difficulty" },
	{ "question": "革新", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "reform; innovation" },
	{ "question": "頭痛", "answers": [ "ずつう" ], "comment": "headache" },
	{ "question": "額面", "answers": [ "がくめん" ], "comment": "face value; par" },
	{ "question": "食欲", "answers": [ "しょくよく" ], "comment": "appetite (for food)" },
	{ "question": "養蚕", "answers": [ "ようさん" ], "comment": "sericulture; silkworm culture" },
	{ "question": "首脳", "answers": [ "しゅのう" ], "comment": "head; leader; leading spirit\nimportant part" },
	{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね" ], "comment": "knack; skill; trick; secret; know-how; the ropes; hang\nbone\nframe\noutline; core\nbackbone; spirit; fortitude\nlaborious; troublesome; difficult" },
	{ "question": "骨身", "answers": [ "ほねみ" ], "comment": "flesh and bones" },
	{ "question": "高層", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "multistory; multistoried; high-rise; high; tall" },
	{ "question": "黒潮", "answers": [ "くろしお" ], "comment": "Japan Current; Kuroshio Current" }
]
}
